the following is a conversation with
以下是与之对话
jurgen schmidhuber he's the co-director
jurgen schmidhuber他是联合主任
of a CSA a lab and a co-creator of long
CSA的实验室和长期的共同创造者
short term memory networks LS TMS are
短期记忆网络LS TMS是
used in billions of devices today for
今天在数十亿设备中用于
speech recognition translation and much
语音识别 翻译等等
more over 30 years he has proposed a lot
更超过 30年，他提出了很多
of interesting out-of-the-box ideas a
有趣的开箱即用的想法
meta learning adversarial networks
元学习对抗网络
computer vision and even a formal theory
计算机 视觉 甚至是形式理论
of quote creativity curiosity and fun
引用创造力的好奇心和乐趣
this conversation is part of the MIT
这次谈话是麻省理工学院的一部分
course and artificial general
课程和人工将军
intelligence and the artificial
智力和人工
intelligence podcast if you enjoy it
智能播客， 如果你喜欢它
subscribe on youtube itunes or simply
订阅youtube itunes或简单
connect with me on twitter at Lex
在 Lex的 Twitter上与我联系
Friedman spelled Fri D and now here's my
弗里德曼拼写了Fri D，现在这里是我的
conversation with jurgen schmidhuber
与jurgen schmidhuber交谈
early on you dreamed of AI systems that
早在你梦见人工智能系统的时候
self-improve recursively when was that
那是什么时候递归地自我提升
dream born when I was a baby
我小时候就梦见了
no it's not true I mean it was a
不， 这不是真的 我的意思是它是一个
teenager and what was the catalyst for
少年和什么是催化剂
that birth what was the thing that first
那出生究竟是什么东西 ，第一
inspired you when I was a boy I'm I was
当我还是个男孩的时候，我就是这样鼓舞我的
thinking about what to do in my life and
想在 我的生命 做什么，
then I thought the most exciting thing
然后我想到了最激动人心的事情
is to solve the riddles of the universe
是解决宇宙的谜语
and and that means you have to become a
而且这意味着你必须成为一个
physicist however then I realized that
物理学家然后我意识到了
there's something even grander you can
你可以有更大的东西
try to build a machine that isn't really
尝试建立一个机器， 是不是 真的
a machine any longer that learns to
一台 学会了的机器
become a much better physicist than I
成为一个比我更好的物理学家
could ever hope to be and that's how I
可能希望 成为 ，我就是这样
thought maybe I can multiply my tiny
想也许我可以繁殖我的小事
little bit of creativity into infinity
创意 点点 变成无穷大
but ultimately that creativity will be
但最终 会有创造力
multiplied to understand the universe
乘以了解宇宙
around us that's that's the the
我们周围 就是那个
curiosity for that mystery that that
那个神秘的好奇心就是那个
drove you yes so if you can build a
如果你能建立一个，那就开车送你
machine that learns to solve more and
学会解决更多问题的机器
more complex problems and more and more
更复杂的问题越来越多
general problems older then you
一般问题比你年长
basically have solved all the problems
基本上已经解决了所有问题
at least all the solvable problems so
至少 所有可解决的问题都是 如此
how do you think what is the mechanism
你觉得这个 机制怎么样？
for that kind of general solver look
对于那种一般的求解器外观
like obviously we don't quite yet have
像我们显然不太 尚无
one or know how to build one who have
一个或知道如何建立一个谁拥有
ideas and you have had throughout your
想法和你在整个你的想法
career several ideas about it so how do
关于它的职业生涯几个想法怎么做
you think about that mechanism so in the
你在考虑这个机制
80s I thought about how to build this
80年代 我想过 如何建立 这个
machine that learns to solve all these
学会解决所有这些问题的机器
problems I cannot solve myself and I
问题我无法解决自己和我
thought it is clear that has to be a
认为很明显 必须是一个
machine that not only learns to solve
机器不仅学会解决
this problem here and
这个问题在这里
problem here but it also has to learn to
这里的问题，但它也有学习
improve the learning algorithm itself so
这样改进了 学习算法本身
it has to have the learning algorithm in
它必须有学习算法
a representation that allows it to
允许 它 的表示
inspect it and modify it such that it
检查并修改 它 ， 使得 它
can come up with a better learning
可以想出更好的学习方法
algorithm so I call that meta learning
算法所以我称之为 元学习
learning to learn and recursive
学习 和递归
self-improvement that is really the
自强不息是 真的
pinnacle of that why you then not only
这就是为什么你不仅如此
alarm how to improve on that problem and
警告如何改善这个问题 和
on that but you also improve the way the
在那，但你也改善了方式
machine improves and you also improve
机器改进，你也改进
the way it improves the way it improves
它改善改进方式的方式
itself and that was my 1987 diploma
本身就是我1987年的文凭
thesis which was all about that
论文就是这样的
hierarchy of metal or knows that I have
金属的等级或知道我有
no computational limits except for the
没有计算限制，除了
well known limits that Google identified
Google确定的众所周知的限制
in 1931 and for the limits our physics
在1931年和我们的物理极限
in the recent years meta learning has
近年来元 学习 有了
gained popularity in a in a specific
在一个 特定的 人群中获得了普及
kind of form you've talked about how
你谈到的那种形式
that's not really meta learning with
这 不是真正的元学习
Newall networks that's more basic
Newall网络更基本
transfer learning can you talk about the
你可以谈谈转学习吗？
difference between the big general meta
大将军之间的差异
learning and a more narrow sense of meta
学习和更狭隘的元感
learning the way it's used today the
学习的方式它是用来今天
ways talked about today let's take the
今天谈论的方式让我们采取的方式
example of a deep neural networks that
深度神经网络的 例子
has learnt to classify images and maybe
已经学会了对图像进行分类，也许
you have trained that network on 100
你已经训练了100个网络
different databases of images and now a
不同的图像数据库，现在是
new database comes along and you want to
新数据库出现了， 你想要
quickly learn the new thing as well so
快速学习 新事物也是 如此
one simple way of doing that as you take
一个简单的方法，你采取这样做
the network which already knows 100
已经知道100的网络
types of databases and then you would
数据库的类型然后你会
just take the top layer of that and you
只需拿出 那个 和你 的顶层
retrain that using the new label data
使用新 标签数据重新培训
that you have in the new image database
你必须 在新的图像数据库
and then it turns out that it really
然后事实证明它真的
really quickly can learn that to one
真的很快可以学习 到 一个
shot basically because from the first
拍摄基本上是因为从第一次
100 data sets
100个数据集
it already has learned so much about
它已经学到了很多东西
about computer vision that it can reuse
关于它可以重复使用的计算机视觉
that and that is then almost good enough
那就那么差不多 了
to solve the new task except you need a
解决新任务，除了你需要一个
little bit of adjustment on the top so
在顶部进行一点调整
that is transfer learning and it has
那就是转学 ，它有
been done in principle for many decades
原则上已经完成了几十年
people have done similar things for
人们 已经 做过类似的 事情
decades meta-learning true mental
几十年的元学习真正的心理
learning is about having the learning
学习是关于学习
algorithm itself open to introspection
算法本身开放内省
by the system that is using it and also
由正在使用它的系统
open to modification such that the
开放修改这样的
learning system has an opportunity to
学习系统有机会
modify any part of the learning
修改学习的任何部分
algorithm and then evaluate the
算法然后 评估
consequences of that modification and
这种修改的后果和
then learn from that to create a better
然后从中学习，创造更好的
learning algorithm and so on recursively
学习算法等递归
so that's a very different animal where
所以这是一个非常不同的动物
you are opening the space of possible
你正在打开可能的空间
learning algorithms to the learning
学习算法学习
system itself right so you've like in
系统本身正确，所以你喜欢
this 2004 paper you described get all
你描述的2004年的论文 得到了所有
machines and programs that we write
我们写的机器和程序
themselves yeah right philosophically
他们自己是 哲学上的权利
and even in your paper mathematically
甚至在数学上你的论文
these are really compelling ideas but
这些是非常引人注目的想法但是
practically do you see these self
你几乎看到了这些自我
referential programs being successful in
参考计划取得成功
the near term to having an impact where
近期有影响的地方
sort of a demonstrates to the world that
一种向世界展示的东西
this direction is a is a good one to
这个 方向是一个很好的方向
pursue in the near term yes we had these
在短期内追求是的，我们有这些
two different types of fundamental
两种不同 类型的基础
research how to build a universal
研究如何建立一个普遍的
problem solver one basically exploiting
问题解决者 基本上是在利用
[Music]
[音乐]
proof search and things like that that
防爆 搜索之类的东西 是
you need to come up with asymptotic Liam
你需要拿出 渐近利亚姆
optimal theoretically optimal
最优理论上最优
self-improvement and problems all of us
我们所有人的 自我改善和 问题
however one has to admit that through
然而， 人们 必须承认，通过
this proof search comes in an additive
这个证据搜索有一个附加物
constant an overhead an additive
不断增加的添加剂
overhead that vanishes in comparison to
与...相比消失的开销
what you have to do to solve large
你需要做些什么来解决大问题
problems however for many of the small
然而，许多小问题
problems that we want to solve in our
我们想要解决的问题
everyday life we cannot ignore this
日常生活我们不能忽视这一点
constant overhead and that's why we also
不断的开销，这就是为什么我们也
have been doing other things non
一直在做其他事情 的非
universal things such as recurrent
普遍的事情，如经常性的
neural networks which are trained by
受过训练的神经网络
gradient descent and local search
梯度下降和本地搜索
techniques which aren't universal at all
根本不普遍的技术
which aren't provably optimal at all
这根本不是最佳选择
like the other stuff that we did but
像我们做其他的东西，但
which are much more practical as long as
这是更实际的， 只要
we only want to solve the small problems
我们只想解决 小问题
that we are
我们是
typically trying to solve in this
通常试图解决这个问题
environment here yes so the universal
环境在这里是的，所以普遍
problem solvers like the girdle machine
问题解决者像腰带机器
but also Markos who does fastest way of
而且 马科斯谁做 的 最快 方法
solving all possible problems which he
解决 他 所有可能出现的问题
developed around 2012 - in my lab they
2012年左右开发的-在我的实验室 ，他们
are associated with these constant
与这些常数相关联
overheads for proof search which
用于证明搜索的开销
guarantee is that the thing that you're
保证是你 的事
doing is optimal for example there is
这样做是最佳 的例子有
this fastest way of solving all problems
这是解决所有问题的最快方法
with a computable solution which is due
使用可计算的解决方案
to Marcus Marcus jota and to explain
马库斯马库斯 霍塔和解释
what's going on there let's take
那里发生 了什么让我们接受
traveling salesman problems with
旅行推销员的问题
traveling salesman problems you have a
你有旅行推销员的问题
number of cities in cities and you try
您尝试过的城市数量
to find the shortest path through all
找到通过所有人 的 最短路径
these cities without visiting any city
这些城市 没有访问 任何城市
twice and nobody know is the fastest way
两次，没有人知道是最快的方式
of solving Traveling Salesman problems
解决旅行商问题
tsps but let's assume there is a method
tsps但我们假设有一种方法
of solving them within n to the 5
在n到 5之间解决它们
operations where n is the number of
操作，其中n是数字
cities then the universal method of
城市然后是普遍的方法
Marcus is going to solve the same
马库斯将解决同样的问题
trolley salesman problem
小车推销员问题
also within n to the 5 steps plus o of 1
也在n到5个步骤加上o的1
plus a constant number of steps that you
加的步骤一个常数 ， 你
need for the proof searcher which you
需要你的证明搜索者
need to show that this particular class
需要表明这个 特殊的类
of problems that Traveling Salesman
旅行推销员 的问题
salesman problems can be solved within a
推销员问题可以解决
certain time bound within order into the
某些时间限制在顺序 中
five steps basically and this additive
基本上是 五步 和这种添加剂
constant doesn't care for in which means
常数并不关心 哪种方式
as n is getting larger and larger as you
因为你越来越大
have more and more cities the constant
有越来越多的 城市不变
overhead pales in comparison and that
与此相比，开销相形见绌
means that almost all large problems
意味着几乎所有大问题
I solved in the best possible way our
我以最好 的方式 解决了 我们的问题
way today we already have a universal
今天 方式 我们已经有了一个普遍的
problem solver like sound however it's
问题解决者，如声音，但它是
not practical because the overhead the
不实用， 因为开销
constant overhead is so large that for
不断的开销是如此之大
the small kinds of problems that we want
我们 想要的那些小问题
to solve in this little biosphere by the
在这个小生物圈中解决
way when you say small you're talking
当你说小说 你说话的时候
about things that fall within the
关于内在 的 事情
constraints of our computational systems
我们的计算系统的限制
thinking they can seem quite large to us
认为他们对我们来说似乎很大
mere humans right that's right yeah so
仅仅是人类，这是对的，是的
they seem large and even unsolvable in a
他们似乎很大，即使在一个不可解
practical sense today but they are still
今天的实际意义，但他们仍然
small compared to almost all problems
与几乎所有问题相比较小
because almost all problems are large
因为几乎所有的问题都很大
problems which are much larger than any
比任何问题都大得多的问题
constant do you find it useful as a
恒你觉得有用 的
person who is dreamed of creating a
梦想创造一个人的人
general learning system has worked on
一般学习系统已经开展
creating one has done a lot of
创建一个 已经做了很多 的
interesting ideas there to think about P
有趣的想法在那里思考 P
versus NP this formalization of how hard
与NP 这种形式化有多么艰难
problems are how they scale this kind of
问题是他们如何扩大这种
worst-case analysis type of thinking do
最坏情况分析的思维类型
you find that useful or is it only just
你会发现有用的还是它只是 刚刚
a mathematical it's a set of
数学它是一组
mathematical techniques to give you
给你的 数学技巧
intuition about what's good and bad
关于什么是好的和坏的直觉
mm-hmm so P versus NP that's super
mm-hmm所以P与NP相比是超级的
interesting from a theoretical point of
从理论角度来看很有意思
view and in fact as you are thinking
查看，事实上正如 你所 想
about that problem you can also get
关于那个 问题，你也可以得到
inspiration for better practical
灵感更好实用
problems always on the other hand we
另一方面我们总是存在问题
have to admit that at the moment as he
不得不承认，在 目前 ， 因为 他
best practical problem solvers for all
所有人最好的实际问题解决者
kinds of problems that we are now
各种各样的问题， 我们现在
solving through what is called AI at the
通过所谓的AI来解决
moment they are not of the kind that is
此刻他们 就是那种不
inspired by these questions you know
受到这些 问题的启发你知道
there we are using general-purpose
我们在那里使用 通用
computers such as recurrent neural
计算机，如反复神经
networks but we have a search technique
网络， 但我们有一个搜索技术
which is just local search gradient
这只是本地搜索渐变
descent to try to find a program that is
血统， 试图找到一个程序，它是
running on these recurrent networks such
在这些经常性的网络上运行
that it can
它可以
or some interesting problems such as
或一些 有趣的问题， 如
speech recognition
语音 识别
machine translation and something like
机器翻译 等等
that and there is very little theory
这一点 ， 很少有 理论
behind the best solutions that we have
我们拥有的最佳解决方案背后
at the moment that can do that do you
在你能做到这一点的那一刻
think that needs to change you think
认为需要改变你的想法
that world change or can we go can we
我们可以改变世界，也可以
create a general intelligence systems
创建一个通用 情报系统
without ever really proving that that
没有真正证明那一点
system is intelligent in some kind of
系统 在某种程度上是智能的
mathematical way solving machine
数学方法 解决机器
translation perfectly or something like
翻译完美或类似的东西
that
那
within some kind of syntactic definition
在某种 句法定义中
of a language or can we just be super
一种语言或我们 可以超级
impressed by the thing working extremely
对工作极其深刻的印象深刻
well and that's sufficient there's an
好吧，那就足够 了
old saying and I don't know who brought
老话，我不知道是谁带来的
it up first which says there's nothing
它首先说 什么都没有
more practical than a good theory and um
比一个好的理论和 嗯更实用
yeah and a good theory of
是的和一个好的理论
problem-solving under limited resources
在有限的资源下解决问题
like here in this universe or on this
就像在这个宇宙中或在此
little planet has to take into account
小星球上有考虑
these limited resources and so probably
这些资源有限，很可能
that is locking
那就是锁定
a theory in which is related to what we
一个理论 这是关系到 我们什么
already have sees a sim totally optimal
已经看到一个完全最佳的SIM卡
comes almost which which tells us what
几乎是哪个告诉我们什么
we need in addition to that to come up
我们需要在除了拿出
with a practically optimal problem so
有一个实际上最优的 问题所以
long so I believe we will have something
我相信我们会有 一些东西
like that
这样的
and maybe just a few little tiny twists
也许只是一些小小的曲折
unnecessary to to change what we already
不必改变我们已经拥有的东西
have to come up with that as well as
不得不提出这个以及
long as we don't have that we mmm admit
只要我们没有 那个我们承认
that we are taking sub optimal ways and
我们 采取 次优的方式和
we can y'all not Verizon long shorter
我们可以， 你们不是Verizon长得更短
memory for equipped with local search
内存配备 本地搜索
techniques and we are happy that it
技术，我们很高兴
works better than any competing method
比 任何竞争方法都 更好
but that doesn't mean that we we think
但这并不意味着我们在 思考
we are done you've said that an AGI
我们完成了你说的AGI
system will ultimately be a simple one a
系统最终将是一个简单的a
general intelligent system will
一般智能系统会
ultimately be a simple one maybe a
最终可能是一个简单的
pseudocode of a few lines to be able to
几行的伪代码就可以 了
describe it
形容它
can you talk through your intuition
你能说出你的直觉吗？
behind this idea why you feel that uh at
这背后的想法，为什么你觉得 在 呃
its core intelligence is a simple
它的核心智能很简单
algorithm experience tells us that this
算法经验告诉我们这一点
stuff that works best is really simple
效果最好的东西非常简单
so see asymptotic team optimal ways of
所以看渐近团队的最佳方式
solving problems if you look at them and
如果你看看他们并解决问题
just a few lines of code it's really
它只是 几行代码
true
真正
although they are these amazing
虽然他们是这些惊人的
properties just a few lines of code then
性能 只是几行代码 ，然后
the most promising and most useful
最有前途和最有用的
practical things maybe don't have this
实际的事情也许没有这个
proof of optimality associated with them
与它们相关的最优性证明
however they are so just a few lines of
然而，他们是这么短短的几行
code the most successful mmm we can
编码最成功的mmm我们可以
neural networks you can write them down
神经网络， 你可以写下来
and five lines of pseudocode that's a
和五行伪代码是一个
beautiful almost poetic idea but what
美丽几乎是诗意的想法，但是什么
you're describing there is this the
你在描述有这个
lines of pseudocode are sitting on top
伪代码行坐在上面
of layers and layers
层和 层
abstractions in a sense hmm so you're
某种意义上的抽象， 所以你是
saying at the very top mmm you'll be a
说到最顶端，你会成为一个
beautifully written sort of algorithm
写得很漂亮的算法
but do you think that there's many
但你认为那里有 很多
layers of abstractions we have to first
我们必须首先进行抽象层
learn to construct yeah of course we are
学会建造 我们 当然 是
building on all these great abstractions
建立在所有这些伟大的抽象上
that people have invented over the
人们已经 发明过
millennia such as matrix multiplications
千年如矩阵乘法
and real numbers and basic arithmetic
和实数 和基本算术
and calculus and derivations of error
和微积分和 误差的 推导
functions and derivatives of error
函数和错误的衍生物
functions and stuff like that
功能和类似的东西
so without that language that greatly
没有那种语言那么大
simplifies our way our thinking about
简化了我们思考的方式
these problems we couldn't do anything
这些问题 我们无能为力
so in that sense as always we are
所以在 这个意义上总是我们
standing on the shoulders of the Giants
站在巨人的肩膀上
who in the past simplified the problem
谁过去简化了问题
of problem solving so much that now we
解决这么多问题，现在我们
have a chance to do the final step the
有机会 做最后 一步
final step will be a simple one oh if we
如果我们， 最后一步将是 一个简单的 哦
if you take a step back through all of
如果你退后一步
human civilization in just the universe
宇宙中的人类文明
in check
在检查
how do you think about evolution and
你怎么看待 进化 和
what if creating a universe is required
如果需要创建一个Universe会怎样
to achieve this final step what if going
实现这最后一步，如果去的话
through the very painful and an
通过非常痛苦和一个
inefficient process of evolution is
低效的进化过程 是
needed to come up with this set of
需要拿出这套
abstractions that ultimately to
最终的抽象
intelligence do you think there's a
情报你认为有吗？
shortcut or do you think we have to
捷径还是你认为我们必须这样做
create something like our universe in
创造像我们的 宇宙 一样的东西
order to create something like human
为了创造 像 人类 这样的东西
level intelligence hmm so far the only
到目前为止，唯一的水平情报
example we have is this one this
我们的例子就是这个
universe and you live you better maybe
宇宙，你可能生活得更好
not but we are part of this whole
不是，但我们 是 整体的 一部分
process right so apparently so it might
过程 权利 显然是如此
be the key is that the code that runs
可关键 是运行该代码
the universe as
宇宙为
really really simple everything points
真的很简单
to that possibility because gravity and
这种 可能性因为引力和
other basic forces are really simple
其他基本力量非常简单
laws that can be easily described also
也很容易描述的法律
in just a few lines of code basically
基本上只需几行代码
and and then there are these other
然后还有其他这些
events that the apparently random events
那些明显随机事件的事件
in the history of the universe which as
在宇宙的历史中 ，作为
far as we know at the moment don't have
据 我们所知，目前 还没有
a compact code but who knows maybe
一个紧凑的代码但谁知道也许
somebody and the near future is going to
有人和不久的将来会去
figure out the pseudo-random generator
计算出的伪随机数发生器
which is which is computing whether the
哪个是计算是否
measurement of that spin up or down
测量旋转上升或下降
thing here is going to be positive or
这里的事情将是积极的 或
negative underlying quantum mechanics
负面的 量子力学
yes so you ultimately think quantum
是的， 所以你最终会想到 量子
mechanics is a pseudo-random number
mechanics是一个伪随机数
generator monistic there's no randomness
发电机一元论没有随机性
in our universe does God play dice so a
在我们的宇宙中，上帝会玩骰子
couple of years ago a famous physicist
几年 前 是一位着名的物理学家
quantum physicist Anton Zeilinger he
量子物理学家Anton Zeilinger 他
wrote an essay in nature and it started
在自然界写了一篇文章并开始了
more or less like that one of the
或多或少喜欢 那个
fundamental insights our theme of the
基本见解我们的主题
20th century was that the universe is
20世纪是宇宙是
fundamentally random on the quantum
从根本上随机的量子
level and that whenever you measure spin
等级和每当你测量旋转
up or down or something like that a new
向上或向下或 类似于新的东西
bit of information enters the history of
一点点信息进入了历史
the universe and while I was reading
宇宙和我在读书的时候
that I was already typing the responds
我已经输入了 响应
and they had to publish it because I was
他们不得不发布它， 因为我是
right that there's no evidence no
对， 没有证据没有
physical evidence for that so there's an
这方面的物证就是这样
alternative explanation where everything
一切都在另类解释
that we consider random is actually
我们认为随机是实际的
pseudo-random such as the decimal
伪随机如小数
expansion of pi
扩展pi
supply is interesting because every
供应很有趣，因为每一个
three-digit sequence every sequence of
每个序列的三位数序列
three digits appears roughly one in a
三位数大致出现在一个数字中
thousand times and every five digit
千位和每五位数
sequence appears roughly one in ten
序列出现大约十分之一
thousand times what do you really would
千倍的你 真的会
expect if it was run random but there's
期待它是否随机运行但是有
a very short algorithm short program
一个非常 短的算法短 程序
that computes all of that so it's
计算所有这些就是这样
extremely compressible and who knows
非常可压缩 ，谁知道
maybe tomorrow somebody some grad
也许明天有人会毕业
student at CERN goes back over all these
欧洲核子研究中心的学生回顾了所有这些
data points better decay and whatever
数据点更好腐烂等等
and figures out oh it's the second
并计算出 哦，这是第二个
billion digits of pi or something like
pi 等十亿个数字
that we don't have any fundamental
我们没有任何根本
reason at the moment to believe that
此刻有理由相信这一点
this is truly random and not just a
这是真正的随机而不仅仅是一个
deterministic video game if it was a
确定性视频游戏，如果它是一个
deterministic video game it would be
这将是确定性的视频游戏
much more beautiful because beauty is
更漂亮因为美丽
simplicity and many of the basic laws of
简单和许多的基本规律
the universe like gravity and the other
宇宙等 重力 和 其他
basic forces are very simple so very
基本力量非常简单
short programs can explain what these
简短的程序可以解释这些
are doing and and it would be awful and
正在做的和，这将是可怕的 和
ugly the universe would be ugly the
丑陋的宇宙将 是丑陋的
history of the universe would be ugly if
如果 ，宇宙的历史将是丑陋的
for the extra things the random the
对于额外的东西随机的
seemingly random data points that we get
我们得到的看似随机的数据点
all the time that we really need a huge
我们真的需要一个巨大的时间
number of extra bits to destroy all
破坏所有的额外位数
these um these extra bits of information
这些是额外的信息
so as long as we don't have evidence
所以只要我们没有 证据
that there is no short program that
没有短期计划，
computes the entire history of the
计算的整个历史
entire universe we are a scientists
整个宇宙我们 是科学家
compelled to look further for that Swiss
不得不进一步 寻找瑞士人
program your intuition says there exists
编程你的直觉说存在
a shortest a program that can backtrack
一个可以回溯的最短程序
to the to the creation of the universe
到了宇宙的创造
so the shortest path to the creation yes
所以 创作 的最短 路径是
including all the
包括所有的
entanglement things and all the spin
纠缠的东西和所有的旋转
up-and-down measurements that have been
已经 上下的测量
taken place since 13.8 billion years ago
发生在138亿年前
and so yeah so we don't have a proof
所以是的， 所以我们没有证据
that it is random we don't have a proof
这是 随机的，我们没有证据
of that it is compressible to a short
它 是可压缩的短
program but as long as we don't have
程序，但只要 我们没有
that proof we are obliged as scientists
这证明 我们有义务作为科学家
to keep looking for that simple
继续寻找那么简单
explanation absolutely so you said
绝对的解释，所以你说
simplicity is beautiful or beauty is
简约美丽或美丽
simple either one works but you also
简单的任何一个有效，但你也
work on curiosity discovery
致力于好奇心的发现
you know the romantic notion of
你知道浪漫的概念
randomness of serendipity of being
存在的意外随机性
surprised by things that are about you
对你有关的事情感到惊讶
kind of in our poetic notion of reality
我们诗意的现实观念
we think as humans require randomness so
我们认为人类需要随机性
you don't find randomness beautiful you
你不觉得随机性美丽的你
use you find simple determinism
用你找到简单的决定论
beautiful yeah okay so why why because
美丽呀好了，为什么，为什么 ，因为
the explanation becomes shorter a
解释变得更短了
universe that is compressible to a short
可压缩到短的宇宙
program is much more elegant and much
程序 更优雅，更多
more beautiful than another one which
比另一个更漂亮其中
needs an almost infinite number of bits
需要比特的几乎无限数目
to be described as far as we know many
据我们所知，有很多人要描述
things that are happening in this
事情在 这发生
universe are really simple in terms are
宇宙是在 条件非常简单的
from short programs that compute gravity
来自计算引力的短程序
and the interaction between elementary
和小学之间的互动
particles and so on so all of that seems
所以 这 一切 似乎 都是 颗粒等等
to be very very simple every electron
每个电子都 非常简单
seems to reuse the same sub program all
似乎重用了所有相同的子程序
the time as it is interacting with other
它 与其他人 互动 的时间
elementary particles if we now require
基本粒子， 如果我们现在需要
an extra Oracle injecting new bits of
一个额外的Oracle注入新的
information all the time for these extra
所有信息的时间 ，这些额外的
things which are currently no
目前 没有的 东西
understood such as
理解如
better decay then the whole description
更好的腐烂然后整个描述
length our data that we can observe out
长 我们的 数据，我们可以观察 出
of the history of the universe would
宇宙的历史会
become much longer and therefore uglier
变得更长，因此更加丑陋
and uglier
和丑陋的
again the simplicity is elegant and
再简单优雅
beautiful all the history of science is
美丽的所有科学史都是
a history of compression progress yes so
压缩进度的历史 是这样的
you've described sort of as we build up
你已经描述了我们建立起来的那种
abstractions and you've talked about the
抽象，你已经谈到了
idea of compression how do you see this
压缩的想法你怎么看这个
the history of science the history of
科学史的历史
humanity our civilization and life on
人类我们的文明和生活
earth as some kind of path towards
地球作为某种 通往的道路
greater and greater compression what do
压力越大越好
you mean by there how do you think of
你的意思是你怎么想 的
that indeed the history of science is a
确实，科学史是一个
history of compression progress what
压缩历史进展如何
does that mean hundreds of years ago
这意味着数百年前
there was an astronomer whose name was
有一位名叫天文学家的天文学家
Keppler and he looked at the data points
凯普勒 和他看着数据点
that he got by watching planets move and
他通过观察行星移动得到了
then he had all these data points and
然后他有所有这些数据点和
suddenly turnouts that he can greatly
突然间，他可以大大改善投票率
compress the data by predicting it
通过预测来压缩数据
through an ellipse law so it turns out
事实证明，通过椭圆定律
that all these data points are more or
所有这些数据点都更多或更多
less on ellipses around the Sun and
更少关于太阳和周围的椭圆
another guy came along whose name was
另一个人的名字来了
Newton and before him hook and they said
牛顿和他之前 挂钩，他们说
the same thing that is making these
同样的事情正在制造 这些
planets move like that is what makes the
行星移动就像是这样的
apples fall down and it also holds form
苹果掉下来，它也有 形式
stones and for all kinds of other
石头和各种其他
objects and suddenly many many of these
对象，突然间有很多这些
compression of these observations became
压缩 这些观察 成了
much more compressible because as long
更可压缩 因为只要
as you can predict the next thing given
因为你可以预测下一件事
what you have seen so far you can
到目前为止你所看到的你可以
compress it you don't have to store that
压缩它你 不必 存储它
data extra this is called predict
数据额外 这称为预测
coding and then there was still
编码然后还有
something wrong with that theory of the
那个理论的 错误
universe and you had deviations from
宇宙和 你 有偏差
these predictions of the theory and 300
这些理论的预测和 300
years later another guy came along whose
年后， 另一个人一起来到 其
name was Einstein and he he was able to
名字是爱因斯坦和他他能够
explain away all these deviations from
解释所有这些偏差
the predictions of the old theory
旧理论的预测
through a new theory which was called
通过一种被称为的新理论
the general theory of relativity which
广义相对论
at first glance looks a little bit more
乍一看 看起来多一点
complicated and you have to warp space
复杂， 你必须 扭曲空间
and time but you can't phrase it within
和时间， 但你不能在内部说出来
one single sentence which is no matter
一句话也 没关系
how fast you accelerate and how fast are
如何快速你加速和速度有多快
hard you decelerate and no matter what
很难 减速，无论如何
is the gravity in your local framework
是 你 本地框架中 的引力
Lightspeed always looks the same and
Lightspeed总是看起来一样
from from that you can calculate all the
从那你可以 计算 所有
consequences so it's a very simple thing
后果所以这是一件非常简单的事情
and it allows you to further compress
它可以让你进一步压缩
all the observations because suddenly
突然之间的 所有观察
there are hardly any deviations any
几乎不存在 任何偏差
longer that you can measure from the
不再是那个 可以从测量
predictions of this new theory so all of
对这一新理论的预测如此全部
science is a history of compression
科学是压缩的历史
progress you never arrive immediately at
你永远不会 马上 到达的进步
the shortest explanation of the data but
对数据的最短解释 但是
you're making progress whenever you are
无论何时，你都在取得进步
making progress you have an insight you
进取你有 你 的洞察力
see all first I needed so many bits of
先看看我 需要这么多的东西
information to describe the data to
描述数据的信息
describe my falling apples my video are
用我的视频描述我堕落的苹果
falling apples I need so many data so
掉苹果我需要这么多数据
many pixels have to be stored but then
必须存储许多像素，但随后
suddenly I realize no there is a very
突然间我意识到没有一个非常
simple way of predicting the third frame
预测 第三帧的 简单方法
in the video from the first tool and and
从 第一工具的视频和
maybe not every little detail can be
也许不是每一个细节都可以
predicted but more or less most of these
预测但或多或少 的 大部分 这些
orange blocks blobs that are coming down
橙色块blob下降
they accelerate in the same way which
它们以同样的方式加速
means that I can greatly compress the
意味着我可以大大压缩
video and the amount of compression
视频和压缩量
progress that is the depth of the
这是的深度进展
insight that you have at that moment
你当时的 洞察力
that's the fun that you have the
这就是你 有 乐趣
Scientific fun that fun in that
有趣的科学乐趣
discovery and we can build artificial
发现，我们可以建立人工
systems that do the same thing they
他们做同样 事情的系统
measure the depth of their insights as
衡量他们的见解的深度
they are looking at the data which is
他们正在查看数据
coming in through their own experiments
通过他们自己的实验进来
and we give them a reward an intrinsic
我们给他们一个内在的奖励
reward and proportion to this depth of
奖励和这个深度的比例
insight and since they are trying to
洞察力和，因为他们 正试图
maximize the rewards they get they are
最大化他们获得的奖励
suddenly motivated to come up with new
突然有动力想出新的
action sequences with new experiments
动作序列与新实验
that have the property that the data
具有该数据的属性
that is coming in as a consequence are
正在进入一个后果 是
these experiments has the property that
这些实验具有这样的特性
they can learn something about see a
他们可以学到一些关于看到的东西
pattern in there which they hadn't seen
他们没见过的那种模式
yet before so there's an idea of power
然而之前就有了权力的概念
play you've described a training general
玩你描述了一个训练将军
problem solver in this kind of way of
这种方式的问题解决者
looking for the unsolved problems
寻找 未解决的问题
yeah can you describe that idea a little
是的，你可以描述这个想法 一点点
further it's another very simple idea so
进一步 它的另一个非常简单的想法，以便
normally what you do in computer science
通常你在计算机科学中做什么
you have you have some guy who gives you
你有一些人 给你
a problem and then there is a huge
一个问题然后有一个巨大的
search space of potential solution
寻找潜在解决方案的空间
candidates and you somehow try them out
候选人和你以某种方式尝试它们
and you have more less sophisticated
而且你的 成熟度更低
ways of moving around in that search
在搜索 走动的方式
space until you finally found a solution
空间直到你终于找到了解决方案
which you consider satisfactory that's
你认为 这 是令人满意的
what most of computer science is about
大多数计算机科学是关于什么的
power play just goes one little step
权力发挥 只是迈出了一小步
further and says let's not only search
进一步说，让我们不仅搜索
for solutions to a given problem but
对于给定的问题 的解决方案 ，但
let's search two pairs of problems and
让我们搜索两对问题和
their solutions where the system itself
他们的解决方案系统本身
has the opportunity to phrase its own
有机会说出自己的话
problem so we are looking suddenly at
问题所以我们突然看着
pairs of problems and their solutions or
一对问题及其 解决方案或
modifications are the problems over that
修改是那个问题
is supposed to generate a solution to
应该生成一个解决方案
that
那
new problem and and this additional
新问题和这个额外的
degree of freedom allows us to build
自由度使我们能够建立
Korea systems that are like scientists
像科学家一样的韩国系统
in the sense that they not only try to
在这个意义上，他们 不仅试图
solve and try to find answers to
解决并试图找到答案
existing questions no they are also free
现有问题 不是他们也是免费的
to impose their own questions so if you
如果你这么强加自己的问题
want to build an artificial scientist we
我想建立一个人工科学家
have to give it that freedom and power
必须赋予它 自由 和力量
play is exactly doing that so that's
玩正是这样做的
that's a dimension of freedom that's
这是一个自由的维度
important to have but how do you are
很重要，但你是怎么做的
hardly you think that
你几乎没想到
how multi-dimensional and difficult the
如何多维和难点
space of them coming up in your
他们的空间出现在 你的
questions is yeah so as as it's one of
问题是的，因为它是一个
the things that as human beings we
我们作为人类的事物
consider to be the thing that makes us
认为是让我们成为的东西
special the intelligence that makes us
特别是使我们的智慧
special is that brilliant insight yeah
特别是那才华横溢啊
that can create something totally new
这可以创造一些全新的东西
yes so now let's look at the extreme
是的所以现在让我们看看极端
case let's look at the set of all
让我们来看看 所有 的一套
possible problems that you can formally
你可以正式提出的问题
describe which is infinite which should
描述哪个应该是无限的
be the next problem that a scientist or
是 科学家或者科学家 的下一个问题
power-play is going to solve well it
强力发挥 将很好地解决它
should be the easiest problem that goes
应该是最简单的问题
beyond what you already know
超越你已经知道的
so it should be the simplest problem
所以它应该是最简单的问题
that the current problems all of that
目前所有的问题都存在
you have which can already sold 100
你有哪些 已售出100
problems that he cannot solve yet by
问题 是他无法通过尚未解决
just generalizing so it has to be new so
只是概括所以它必须是新的，从而
it has to require a modification of the
它必须要求修改
problem solver such that the new problem
问题解决者这样的新问题
solver can solve this new thing but the
解决者可以解决这个新事物但是
old problem solver cannot do it
老问题解决者做不到
and in addition to that we have to make
除了我们必须做的
sure that the problem solver doesn't
确保问题解决者不
forget any of the previous solutions
忘记以前的任何解决方案
right and so by definition power play is
正确，所以定义权力发挥是
now trying always to search and this
现在总是试图搜索和这个
pair of in in the set of pairs of
在成对的一对中
problems and problems over modifications
修改的问题和问题
for a combination that minimize the time
对于最小化 时间 的组合
to achieve these criteria so as always
一如既往地实现这些标准
trying to find the problem which is
试图找到问题所在
easiest to add to the repertoire so just
最容易添加到保留曲目中
like grad students and academics and
喜欢研究生和学者
researchers can spend the whole career
研究人员可以度过整个 职业生涯
in a local minima hmm
在局部最小值嗯
stuck trying to come up with interesting
坚持试图拿出有趣的东西
questions but ultimately doing very
问题，但最终做得很好
little do you think it's easy well in
你觉得它很容易很好
this approach of looking for the
这种寻找方法
simplest unsolvable problem to get stuck
卡住最简单的无法解决的问题
in a local minima is not never really
在当地的最小值并不是真的
discovering new you know really jumping
发现新的你知道真正的跳跃
outside of the hundred problems the very
非常的问题之外
solved in a genuine creative way no
以真正的创造性方式解决了
because that's the nature of power play
因为这是权力游戏的本质
that it's always trying to break its
它 总是试图打破它
current generalization abilities by
当前的泛化能力
coming up with a new problem which is
来了 一个新的问题，就是
beyond the current horizon
超越当前的视野
just shifting the horizon of knowledge a
只是改变知识的视野a
little bit out there breaking the
有点破坏了
existing rules
现有规则
search says the new thing becomes
搜索说新事物变成了
solvable but wasn't solvable by the old
可以解决， 但老年人无法解决
thing so like adding a new axiom like
像添加新公理一样的事情
what Google did when he came up with
谷歌是什么，当他想出了
these new sentences new theorems that
这些新句子的新定理
didn't have a proof in the phone system
在电话系统中没有证据
which means you can add them to the
这意味着你可以将它们添加到
repertoire
剧目
hoping that that they are not going to
希望他们不打算
damage the consistency of the whole
损害整体的一致性
thing so in the paper with the amazing
所以在纸上带着 惊人的东西
title formal theory of creativity fun in
创意趣味称号正式理论
intrinsic motivation you talk about
你谈到的内在动机
discovery as intrinsic reward so if you
发现作为内在的奖励，如果你
view humans as intelligent agents what
将人视为智能代理人的 东西
do you think is the purpose and meaning
你认为是目的和意义吗？
of life far as humans is you've talked
远离人类的生活，你已经谈过了
about this discovery do you see humans
关于这个发现，你看到人类吗？
as an instance of power play
作为权力游戏的一个例子
agents yeah so humans are curious and
特工是的， 所以人类很好奇
that means they behave like scientists
这意味着他们表现 得像科学家一样
not only the official scientists but
不仅 是 官方科学家，而且
even the babies behave like scientists
甚至婴儿的 行为也像科学家一样
and they play around with toys to figure
他们玩玩具来玩
out how the world works and how it is
了解世界是 如何 运作的以及 它是如何 运作的
responding to their actions and that's
响应 他们的行动，这就是
how they learn about gravity and
他们如何了解重力和
everything and yeah in 1990 we had the
一切，是的，1990年我们 有
first systems like the hand would just
像手一样的第一个系统就是这样
try to to play around with the
尝试玩弄的
environment and come up with situations
环境和想出的情况
that go beyond what they knew at that
超越他们知道在什么
time and then get a reward for creating
时间，然后获得 奖励 ，用于创建
these situations and then becoming more
这些情况然后变得更多
general problem solvers and being able
一般问题解决者和能够
to understand more of the world so yeah
了解更多的世界， 所以是的
I think in principle that that that
我原则上认为那就是那个
curiosity strategy or sophisticated
好奇策略或复杂
versions of whether chess is quiet they
国际象棋是否安静的版本
are what we have built-in as well
是我们内置的
because evolution discovered that's a
因为进化论发现 它是一个
good way of exploring the unknown world
探索未知世界的好方法
and a guy who explores the unknown world
还有一个探索未知世界的人
has a higher chance of solving problems
有更高的机会 解决问题
that he needs to survive in this world
他需要 在这个世界上生存
on the other hand those guys who were
另一方面那些家伙
too curious they were weeded out as well
太好奇了，他们也被淘汰了
so you have to find this trade-off
所以你必须 找到 这种权衡
evolution found a certain trade-off
进化发现了一定的权衡
apparently in our society there are as a
显然在我们的社会中有一个
certain percentage of extremely
一定比例的极端
exploitive guy
剥削的家伙
and it doesn't matter if they die
如果他们死了没关系
because many of the others are more
因为许多其他人更多
conservative and and and so yeah it
保守和等等，是的
would be surprising to me if if that
将是令人吃惊， 我如果如果
principle of artificial curiosity
人工好奇的原则
wouldn't be present and almost exactly
不会出现，几乎完全
the same form here in our brains
我们脑中的形式相同
so you're a bit of a musician and an
所以你是一个 音乐家和一个
artist so continuing on this topic of
艺术家继续 这个话题
creativity what do you think is the role
创意你认为是什么角色
of creativity and intelligence so you've
创造力 和智慧，所以你
kind of implied that it's essential for
有点暗示它是必不可少的
intelligence if you think of
你想到的情报
intelligence as a problem-solving system
智力作为一个解决问题的系统
as ability to solve problems but do you
作为解决 问题的 能力， 但你呢？
think it's essential this idea of
认为这是至关重要 的
creativity we never have a program a sub
创造力我们永远不会有一个子程序
program that is called creativity or
被称为创造力或
something it's just a side effect of
东西它只是一个副作用
when our problem solvers do they are
当我们的问题解决者做的时候
searching a space of problems or a space
寻找问题 或空间的空间
of candidates of solution candidates
候选人候选人
until they hopefully find a solution to
直到他们希望 找到解决方案
have given from them but then there are
从他们 给出 ，但后来有
these two types of creativity and both
这两种创造力 都兼而有之
of them are now present in our machines
它们现在存在于我们的机器中
the first one has been around for a long
第一个已经存在了很长时间
time which is human gives problem to
人类的时间问题
machine machine tries to find a solution
机机试图找到一个 解决方案
to that and this has been happening for
对此，这一直在发生
many decades and for many decades
几十年和几十年
machines have found creative solutions
机器找到了创造性的解决方
to interesting problems where humans
人类有趣的问题
were not aware of these particularly in
不知道这些特别是在
creative solutions but then appreciated
创意解决方案但后来赞赏
that the machine found that the second
机器发现了第二个
is the pure creativity that I would call
我会称之为纯粹的创造力
what I just mentioned I would call the
我刚刚提到的我会 称之为
applied creativity like applied art
应用创造力，如应用 艺术
where somebody tells you now make a nice
有人告诉你现在做的很好
picture off of this Pope and you will
这个教皇的照片，你会的
get money for that okay so here is the
为此获得金钱， 所以这里 是
artist and he makes a convincing picture
艺术家和他做了一个令人信服的画面
of the Pope and the Pope likes it and
教皇和教皇都喜欢和
gives him the money
给了他钱
and then there is the pure creative
然后就是纯粹的创意
creativity which is more like the power
创造力更像是 力量
play and the artificial curiosity thing
玩耍和人工好奇的事情
where you have the freedom to select
你有自由 选择的地方
your own problem like a scientist who
你自己的问题就像一个科学家
defines his own question to study and so
定义他自己要研究的问题等等
that is the pure creativity of UL and
这是UL和。 的纯粹创造力
opposed to the applied creativity which
反对应用的创造力
serves another and in that distinction
服务于另一个并且在那个区别
there's almost echoes of narrow AI
几乎没有缩小AI的回声
versus general AI so this kind of
与一般AI相比， 这样
constrained painting of a pope seems
似乎是教皇的约束画
like the the approaches of what people
喜欢什么人的方法
are calling narrow AI and pure
正在呼吁缩小AI和纯粹
creativity seems to be maybe I'm just
创造力似乎也许我只是
biased as a human but it seems to be an
作为一个人有偏见，但它似乎是一个
essential element of human level
人的基本要素
intelligence is that what you're
智慧 就是你所拥有的
implying
这意味着
to a degree if you zoom back a little
如果你缩小一点 ， 在 某种程度上
bit and you just look at a general
有点你只看一般
problem-solving machine which is trying
解决问题的机器正在尝试
to solve arbitrary problems then this
这解决任意问题
machine will figure out in the course of
机器将在过程中弄清楚
solving problems that it's good to be
解决问题 ，这是很好的
curious so all of what I said just now
好奇， 所以 我刚刚说的话
about this prewired curiosity and this
关于这个prewired的好奇心和这个
will to invent new problems that the
将发明的新问题
system doesn't know how to solve yet
系统还不知道如何解决
should be just a byproduct of the
应该只是一个副产品
general search however apparently
然而，一般搜索显然
evolution has built it into us because
进化 已经建立在 我们身上，因为
it turned out to be so successful a
结果证明是如此成功
pre-wiring a buyer's a very successful
预先布线 买家 是非常成功的
exploratory buyers that that we are born
我们出生的 探索性 买家
with and you've also said that
和你说的那样
consciousness in the same kind of way
意识以同样的方式
may be a byproduct of problem-solving
可能是 解决问题 的副产品
you know do you think do you find it's
你知道你认为你发现它吗？
an interesting by-product you think it's
你认为它是一个有趣的副产品
a useful by-product what are your
有用的副产品 是什么？
thoughts on consciousness in general or
关于一般意识 或 意识的思考
is it simply a byproduct of greater and
它只是一个更大和更好的副产品
greater capabilities of problem-solving
更强 的解决问题的能力
that's that's similar to creativity in
这与创造力相似
that sense yeah we never have a
感觉是的，我们从来没有过
procedure called consciousness in our
我们的程序称为意识
machines however we get as side effects
然而，我们得到了副作用
of what these machines are doing things
这些机器在 做什么
that seem to be closely related to what
这似乎与 什么 密切相关
people call consciousness so for example
例如，人们呼唤意识
in 1990 we had simple systems which were
在1990年，我们有简单的系统
basically recurrent networks and
基本上是经常性的网络和
therefore universal computers trying to
因此通用计算机 试图
map incoming data into actions that lead
将传入的数据映射到导致的操作
to success
成功
maximizing reward in a given environment
在给定环境中最大化奖励
always finding the charging station in
总是找到充电站
time whenever the battery's low and
每当 电池电量 低的时候
negative signals are coming from the
负信号从未来
battery always finds the charging
电池总能找到充电
station in time without bumping against
站在时间而不撞到
painful obstacles on the way so
在路上痛苦的障碍，使
complicated things but very easily
复杂的事情，但很容易
motivated and then we give these little
有动力，然后我们给这些小
a separate we can all network which is
我们可以将所有 网络分开
just predicting what's happening if I do
只是预测如果我这样做会发生什么
that in that what will happen as a
那将会发生什么
consequence of these actions that I'm
这些行为的后果我是
executing and it's just trained on the
执行，它刚刚接受了训练
long and long history of interactions
长期和长期的互动历史
with the world so it becomes a
与 世界如此成为一个世界
predictive model loss of art basically
预测模型基本丧失了艺术
and therefore also a compressor our
因此也是 我们 的压缩机
theme observations after what because
主题意见后 因为什么
whatever you can predict you don't have
无论你能预测到什么，你都没有
to store extras or compression is a side
存储额外的东西或压缩是一方
effect of prediction and how does this
预测的效果 以及如何 做到这一点
record Network impress well it's
记录网络打动 那么它的
inventing little sub programs little sub
发明小子程序小子
Network networks that stand for
代表的网络网络
everything that frequently appears in
经常出现的一切
the environment like bottles and
像瓶子和瓶子这样的环境
microphones and faces maybe lots of
麦克风和面，也许很多
faces in my environment so I'm learning
面对我的环境，所以我正在学习
to create something like a prototype
创建 类似原型的 东西
face and a new face comes along and all
脸和一张新面孔出现 了
I have to encode are the deviations from
我必须编码是偏离
the prototype so it's compressing all
原型所以它压缩所有
the time the stuff that frequently
经常那些东西的时间
appears there's one thing that appears
似乎有一件事出现了
all the time that is present all the
所有的时间都存在
time when the agent is interacting with
代理与之交互的时间
its environment which is the agent
它的环境是代理人
itself
本身
so just for data compression reasons it
所以只是为了数据压缩的原因
is extremely natural for this we can
对 我们 来说这是非常自然的
network to come up with little sub
网络 拿出小分
networks that stand for the properties
代表房产的网络
of the agents the hand you know the the
代理商的手，你知道 的
other actuators and all the stuff that
其他驱动器 和所有的东西 ，
you need to better encode the data which
你需要更好地编码数据
is influenced by the actions of the
受到 行动的 影响
agent so they're just as a side effect
因此，他们只是副作用
of
的
data compression during problem-solving
解决问题时的数据压缩
you have inter myself models now you can
你现在可以拥有自己的模特
use this model of the world to plan your
使用这个世界模型来计划你的
future and that's what yours have done
未来，这就是你所做的
since 1990 so the recurrent Network
自1990年以来经常 网络
which is the controller which is trying
这是正在尝试的控制器
to maximize reward can use this model as
最大限度地奖励可以使用此模型
a network of the what is this model
这个模型 的网络 是什么
network as a wild this predictive model
网络作为一种狂野的预测模型
of the world to plan ahead and say let's
世界要提前计划并说出来
not do this action sequence let's do
不要做这个动作序列让我们这样做
this action sequence instead because it
这个动作序列反而是因为它
leads to more predictor to rewards and
导致更多的预测 奖励和
whenever it's waking up these layers of
每当它醒来 的 这些层
networks let's stand for itself and it's
网络让我们代表本身和 它的
thinking about itself and it's thinking
思考 自己和思考
about itself and it's exploring mentally
关于自己，它在精神上探索
the consequences of its own actions and
自己的行为和后果
and now you tell me what is still
现在你告诉 我什么是静止的
missing missing the next the gap to
失踪失踪接下来的差距 ，
consciousness yeah hi there there isn't
意识是的，那里没有
that's a really beautiful idea that you
这对你来说是一个非常美好的想法
know if life is a collection of data and
知道生命是 数据的 集合 ，
in life is a process of compressing that
在生活中是一个压缩的过程
data to act efficiently you in that data
数据可以有效地处理您的数据
you yourself appear very often so it's
你自己经常出现，所以它是
useful to form compressions of yourself
有助于 形成自己的压缩
and it's a really beautiful formulation
这是一个非常漂亮的配方
of what consciousness is a necessary
什么意识是 必要的
side-effect it's actually quite
副作用实际上是相当的
compelling to me you've described our
引诱我，你已经描述 了我们的
nen's developed LST aims long short-term
nen开发的LST的目标是长期 短期
memory networks the there type of
存储器网络中存在 的 类型
recurrent neural networks they have
他们有复发神经网络
gotten a lot of success recently so
得到了很多成功的最近 如此
these are networks that model the
这些是建模的网络
temporal aspects in the data temporal
数据时间的时间方面
patterns in the data and you've called
你打电话给数据中的模式
them the deepest of the Newell networks
他们是Newell网络中最深的
right so what do you think is the value
对，那么您认为什么是价值
of depth in the models that we use to
在我们习惯的模型中的深度
learn since you mentioned the long
学习，因为你提到了很久
short-term memory and the lsdm I have to
短期记忆和我必须的lsdm
mention the names of the brilliant
提到辉煌的名字
students
学生们
of course that's worse first of all and
当然这 更糟糕 的 是 首先的 和
my first student ever set for writer who
我的第一个学生曾为作家设定过
had fundamental insights already in this
已经有了基本的见解
diploma thesis then Felix Kias had
文凭论文然后 费利克斯基亚斯
additional important contributions Alex
Alex的其他重要贡献
gray is a guy from Scotland who is
格雷是一个来自苏格兰的人
mostly responsible for this
主要负责此事
CTC algorithm which is now often used to
现在经常使用的CTC算法
to train the Alice TM to do the speech
训练Alice TM做演讲
recognition on all the Google Android
对所有Google Android的认可
phones and whatever and Siri and so on
手机和其他什么和Siri 等等
so these guys without these guys I would
所以这些家伙我没有这些家伙
be nothing it's a lot of incredible work
什么都不是， 这是一项令人难以置信的工作
what is now the depth what is the
什么是现在 的深度是什么
importance of depth well
深度的重要性以及
most problems in the real world are deep
现实世界中的大多数问题都很深刻
in the sense that the current input
在当前输入的意义上
doesn't tell you all you need to know
并没有告诉你所有你需要 知道的事情
about the environment mm-hmm so instead
关于环境mm-hmm所以相反
you have to have a memory of what
你必须记住什么
happened in the past and often important
发生在过去，往往很重要
parts of that memory are dated they are
内存部分的日期为他们
pretty old and so when you're doing
很老，所以当你做的时候
speech recognition for example and
语音识别例如 和
somebody says eleven then that's about
有人说十一，那就是
half a second or something like that
半秒或类似的东西
which means it's already fifty-eight
这意味着它已经 五十八岁了
time steps and another guy or the same
时间步骤和另一个 人或相同
guy says seven so the ending is the same
家伙说七，所以结局是一样的
Evan but now the system has to see the
埃文，但现在系统必须 看到
distinction between seven and eleven and
七和十一之间的区别
the only way I can see the differences
我能看到差异的唯一方法
it has to store that fifty steps ago
五十步之前它必须存储
there wasn't or a nerve eleven or seven
没有或神经 十一或七
so there you have already a problem of
所以你已经有了问题
depth fifty because for each time step
深度五十，因为 每个时间 步
you have something like a virtual a
你有 像 虚拟的 东西
layer and the expanded unrolled version
图层和 展开的展开版本
of this Riccar network which is doing
这个正在做的Riccar网络
the speech recognition so these long
语音识别所以这些很长
time lags they translate into problem
时间滞后他们转化为问题
depth and most problems and this world
深度和大多数问题和这个世界
Asajj that you really have to look far
Asajj， 你真的 要远远看
back in time
回到过去
to understand what is the problem and to
了解问题是什么和
solvent but just like with our CMS you
溶剂但就像我们的CMS 你
don't necessarily need to when you look
当你看的时候不一定需要
back in time remember every aspect you
回到过去，记住你的每一个方面
just need to remember the important
只需记住重要的事情
aspects that's right the network has to
这方面正确的 网络 必须
learn to put the important stuff in into
学会把重要的东西放进去
memory and to ignore the unimportant
内存，并忽略 不重要
noise so but in that sense deeper and
噪声，但在这个意义上更深
deeper is better or is there a
更深更好或有没有
limitation is is there
是有限制的
I mean LCM is one of the great examples
我的意思是LCM是 一个很好的例子
of architectures that do something
架构 是 做一些事情
beyond just deeper and deeper networks
超越 更深层次的网络
there's clever mechanisms for filtering
有巧妙的过滤机制
data for remembering and forgetting so
记住和遗忘的数据
do you think that that kind of thinking
你认为 这种想法的
is necessary if you think about LCM is a
如果你认为LCM是一个必要的话
leap a big leap forward over traditional
与传统相比，实现了跨越式发展
vanilla are nuns what do you think is
香草是修女你觉得怎么样？
the next leap hmm it within this context
在这种背景下，它的下一个飞跃
so LCM is a very clever improvement but
所以LCM 是一个非常聪明的 改进但是
LCM still don't have the same kind of
LCM仍然没有相同的那种
ability to see far back in the future in
能够远远看到未来
the in the past as us humans do the
在过去，就像我们人类做的那样
credit assignment problem across way
信用分配问题
back not just 50 times steps or a
回不只是 50倍的步骤或
hundred or a thousand but millions and
一百或一千，但数百万
billions it's not clear what are the
数十亿，不清楚是什么
practical limits of the lsdm when it
lsdm的实际限制
comes to looking back already in 2006 I
我已经回顾2006年了
think we had examples where it not only
我认为我们不仅有例子
looked back tens of thousands of steps
回头看了几万步
but really millions of steps and who won
但真的有数百万步，谁赢了
Paris artists in my lab I think was the
我认为 我实验室里的巴黎艺术家 就是 这样
first author of a paper where we really
我们真的是一篇论文的第一作者
was a 2006 or something had examples
是一个2006年或者有什么例子
word learn to look back for more than 10
这个词学会回顾 10 多个
million steps so for most problems of
对于大多数问题，步数为百万步
speech recognition it's not necessary to
语音识别是没有必要
look that far back but there are
看起来那么 远，但有
examples where it does now so looking
它现在如此看的例子
back thing
回来的事
[Music]
[音乐]
that's rather easy because there is only
这很容易， 因为只有
one past but there are many possible
一个过去， 但有很多可能
futures and so a reinforcement learning
期货等强化学习
system which is trying to maximize its
试图最大化 它的系统
future expected rewards and doesn't know
未来的预期奖励并不知道
yet which of these many possible future
然而， 这些可能的未来中的 哪一个
should I select given this one single
我应该选择这个单一的
past it's facing problems that the LCN
过去它面临着LCN的问题
by itself cannot solve so the other sim
本身不能解决因此其他 SIM
is good for coming up with a compact
提出紧凑型产品很有用
representation of the history so far of
到目前为止的历史代表
the history and observations in action
行动中的历史和 观察
so far but now how do you plan in an
到目前为止， 但现在你如何计划
efficient and good way among all these
所有这些中有效和良好的方式
how do you select one of these many
你如何选择这些中的一个
possible action sequences that a
可能的动作序列a
reinforcement learning system has to
强化学习系统必须
consider to maximize reward in this
考虑在这方面最大化奖励
unknown future so again it behaves this
未知的未来所以它再次 表现出来
basic setup where you have one week on
您有 一周的基本设置
network which gets in the video and the
进入视频的网络和
speech and whatever and it's executing
演讲和其他什么，它正在执行
actions and is trying to maximize reward
行动，并试图最大化奖励
so there is no teacher who tells it what
所以没有老师告诉它什么
to do at which point in time and then
做在哪个时间点 ，然后
there's the other network which is
还有另一个网络
just predicting what's going to happen
只是预测会发生什么
if I do that then and that could be an
如果我这样做， 那么 那可能是一个
LCM Network and it allows to look back
LCM 网络，它允许回顾
all the way to make better predictions
一路做出更好的预测
of the next time step so essentially
下一次这么重要
although it's men predicting only the
虽然这是男人只预测的
next time step it is motivated to learn
下一步， 它有动力去学习
to put into memory something that
记忆中的东西
happened maybe a million steps ago
可能发生在一百万步之前
because it's important to memorize that
因为记住这一点很重要
if you want to predict that at the next
如果你想在下一个预测
time step the next event you know how
时间步骤 你知道如何 下一个 事件
can a model of the world like that a
可以像 这样 的世界模型
predictive model of the world be used by
世界 的预测模型通过使用
the first guy let's call it the
第一个让我们称之为
controller and the model the controller
控制器和模型控制器
and the model how can the model be used
和模型如何使用模型
by the controller to efficiently select
由控制器有效选择
among these many possible futures so
在这许多可能的未来中如此
naive way we had about 30 years ago was
我们大约30 年前的天真的方式是
let's just use the model of the world as
让我们只使用 世界 模型
a stand-in as a simulation of the wall
作为墙壁模拟的替身
and millisecond by millisecond we
我们以毫秒为单位
planned the future and that means we
计划 未来，这意味着我们
have to roll it out really in detail and
必须非常 详细地 推出它
it will work only as the model is really
它只会在模型真实的情况下起作用
good and it will still be inefficient
好，它仍然是低效的
because we have to look at all these
因为我们必须看看所有这些
possible futures and and there are so
可能的未来，而且还有
many of them so instead what we do now
其中很多都是 我们现在所做的
since 2015 and our cm systems controller
自2015年起，我们的cm 系统控制器
model systems we give the controller the
模型系统，我们给控制器
opportunity to learn by itself how to
学习自己的机会如何
use the potentially relevant parts of
使用可能相关的部分
the M of the model network to solve new
模型网络的M 解决新的问题
problems more quickly and if it wants to
问题更快 ，如果它想
it can learn to ignore the M and
它可以学会忽略M和
sometimes it's a good idea to ignore the
有时忽略这个是个好 主意
the M because it's really bad it's a bad
M，因为它 真的很糟糕，这很糟糕
predictor in this particular situation
在这种特殊情况下的预测因子
of life where the control is currently
当前控制 的 生命
trying to maximize r1 however it can
试图最大化 r1然而它可以
also allow and to address and exploit
也允许 并解决和利用
some of the sub programs that came about
一些子程序出现了
in the model network through compressing
在模型网络中通过压缩
the data by predicting it so it now has
数据 通过预测它现在 有了
an opportunity to reuse that code the
重用该代码的机会
ethnic information in the modern are
现代的 民族信息 都是
trying to reduce its own search space
试图减少自己的搜索空间
such that it can solve a new problem
这样它就可以解决一个新问题
more quickly than without the model
多 比没有模式迅速
compression so you're ultimately
压缩，所以你最终
optimistic and excited about the power
对权力感到乐观和兴奋
of ra of reinforcement learning in the
加强学习的ra
context of real systems absolutely yeah
真实系统的背景绝对是的
so you see RL as a potential having a
所以你看 RL为 具有 潜在的
huge impact beyond just sort of the M
超出M的巨大影响
part is often develop on supervised
部分经常在监督下发展
learning methods
学习方法
you see RL as a four problems of cell
你认为RL 是细胞 的 四个问题
traffic cars or any kind of applied
交通汽车或任何类型的应用
cyber BOTS X that's the correct
网络BOTS X是正确的
interesting direction for research in
有趣的研究方向
your view I do think so we have a
你的观点我认为我们有一个
company called Mason's Mason's which has
公司称梅森的梅森有
applied to enforcement learning to
适用于执法学习
little Howdy's
小霍迪
there are DS which learn to park without
有没有学会停车的DS
a teacher the same principles were used
老师使用相同的原则
of course so these little Audi's they
当然所以这些小奥迪都是他们的
are small maybe like that so I'm much
很小也许就是这样，所以我很喜欢
smaller than the real Howdy's but they
小于真实的Howdy，但他们
have all the sensors that you find the
拥有你找到的所有传感器
real howdy is you find the cameras that
真正你好是你发现的相机， 这些 相机
lead on sensors they go up to 120 20
在传感器上引导它们达到120 20
kilometres an hour if you if they want
如果他们想要的话，每小时一公里
to and and they are from pain sensors
和和他们 来自疼痛传感器
basically and they don't want to bump
基本上他们不想碰撞
against obstacles and other Howdy's and
对抗障碍和其他你好
so they must learn like little babies to
所以他们必须像小宝宝一样学习
a park take the wrong vision input and
公园采取错误的视力输入和
translate that into actions that lead to
将其 转化为导致的行动
successful packing behavior which is a
成功的包装行为 是一种
rewarding thing and yes they learn that
有益的事情，是的，他们了解到这一点
they are salt we have examples like that
他们盐，我们 有 这样的 例子
and it's only in the beginning this is
而且只有在 开始 的 时候，这 是
just the tip of the iceberg and I
只是冰山一角和我
believe the next wave of a line is going
相信下一波浪潮 即将来临
to be all about that so at the moment
是所有关于这样的时刻
the current wave of AI is about passive
目前的AI浪潮是被动的
pattern observation and prediction
模式观察和预测
and and that's what you have on your
这就是你对 你的所有
smartphone and what the major companies
智能手机和各大 公司
on the Pacific of em are using to sell
在太平洋的 em正在使用出售
you ads to do marketing that's the
你的广告做营销 这就是
current sort of profit in AI and that's
人工智能目前的利润和那种情况
only one or two percent of the world
只占世界的一两个百分点
economy which is big enough to make
经济足够大
these company is pretty much the most
这些公司是最多的
valuable companies in the world but
但是 ，世界上有价值的公司
there's a much much bigger fraction of
有更多的部分
the economy going to be affected by the
经济要由受影响
next wave which is really about machines
下一波真的是关于机器的
that shape the data through our own
通过 我们自己 塑造数据
actions and you think simulation is
行动 ，你认为模拟是
ultimately the biggest way that that
最终这是最大的方式
though those methods will be successful
虽然这些方法会 成功
in the next 10 20 years we're not
在接下来的10年里，我们不是
talking about a hundred years from now
谈论从 现在开始的 一百年
we're talking about sort of the
我们谈论排序的
near-term impact of RL do you think
你认为RL的近期影响
really good simulation is required or is
真正好的模拟是必需的或是
there other techniques like imitation
还有其他技术， 比如模仿
learning you know observing other humans
学习你知道观察其他人类
yeah operating in the real world where
是的，在现实世界里经营
do you think this success will come from
你认为这种成功会来自何方？
so at the moment we have a tendency of
因此现在我们有一个倾向
using physics simulations to learn
使用物理模拟来学习
behavior for machines that learn to
学习机器的行为
solve problems that humans also do not
解决人类 也没有的问题
know how to solve however this is not
知道如何解决，但事实并非如此
the future because the future is and
未来 ，因为 未来是和
what little babies do they don't use a
什么小宝宝他们不 使用
physics engine to simulate the world
物理引擎来模拟世界
no they learn a predictive model of the
没有 他们学习 的 预测模型
world which maybe sometimes is wrong in
世界这 可能有时是错误的
many ways but captures all kinds of
许多方式，但捕获各种各样的
important abstract high-level
重要的抽象高级
predictions which are really important
预测非常重要
to be successful and and that's what is
成功 ， 这就是 成功
what was the future thirty years ago
三十 年前的未来是什么？
when you started that type of research
当你开始这种类型的研究
but it's still the future and now we are
但它仍然是 未来，现在我们是
know much better how to go there to to
知道怎么去那里更好
move there to move forward and to really
移动到那里前进，真的
make working systems based on that where
制作基于其中的工作系统
you have a learning model of the world a
你有一个世界的学习模型a
model of the world that learns to
学习的世界模型
predict what's going to happen if I do
预测如果我这样做会发生什么
that and that
那个和那个
and then the controller uses that model
然后控制器使用该模型
to more quickly learn successful action
更快地 学习成功的行动
sequences and then of course always this
顺序然后当然总是如此
crazy thing in the beginning the model
在模型开始时疯狂的事情
is stupid so the controller should be
是愚蠢所以控制器应该是
motivated to come up with experiments
有动力 想出 实验
with action sequences that lead to data
具有导致数据的动作序列
that improve the model do you think
你认为 改进模型
improving the model constructing an
改进模型构建
understanding of the world in this
在这方面了解世界
connection is the in now the popular
连接是现在流行的
approaches have been successful you know
你知道的方法是成功的
grounded in ideas of neural networks but
以神经网络的思想为基础但是
in the 80s with expert systems there's
在80年代， 有专家系统
symbolic AI approaches which to us
对我们来说，象征性的AI方法
humans are more intuitive in a sense
从某种意义上说，人类更直观
that it makes sense that you build up
你 建立起来 是 有道理的
knowledge in this knowledge
知识这方面的知识
representation what kind of lessons can
代表什么样的课程可以
we draw in our current approaches mmm
我们用当前的方法绘制mmm
for from expert systems from symbolic
来自象征性的专家系统
yeah so I became aware of all of that in
是啊，所以我意识到 在 这一切的
the 80s and back then a logic program
80年代，然后是一个逻辑程序
logic programming was a huge thing was
逻辑编程是一个巨大的东西 是
inspiring to yourself did you find it
你发现它对自己很有启发
compelling because most a lot of your
引人注目，因为大多数你的
work was not so much in that realm mary
工作并不是 那个领域的玛丽
is more in learning systems yes or no
更多是学习系统是或否
but we did all of that so we my first
但我们做了所有这些， 所以我们 第一次
publication ever actually was 1987 was a
实际上是1987年出版的一本书
the implementation of genetic algorithm
遗传算法的实现
of a genetic programming system in
中国遗传规划系统的研究
prologue prologue that's what you learn
这是你所学到的序幕序幕
back then which is a logic programming
那么这是一个逻辑编程
language and the Japanese the anthers
语言和 日本的花药
huge fifth-generation AI project which
巨大的第五代AI项目
was mostly about logic programming back
主要是关于逻辑编程
then although a neural networks existed
然而，虽然存在 神经网络
and were well known back then and deep
并且在当时和深处都是众所周知的
learning has existed since 1965 since
自1965年以来，学习一直存在
this guy and the UK and even anko
这家伙和英国甚至是 anko
started it but
开始吧但是
the Japanese and many other people they
他们是日本人和其他许多人
focus really on this logic programming
真正专注于这种逻辑编程
and I was influenced to the extent that
我被影响的范围内，
I said okay let's take these
我说好了，让我们拿走这些
biologically inspired rules like
生物学启发的规则如
evolution programs and and and implement
进化计划和并实施
that in the language which I know which
用我所知道的那种语言
was Prolog for example back then and
是的Prolog比如 当年和
then in in many ways as came back later
然后在很多方面后来回来
because the Garuda machine for example
因为嘉鲁达 机器 就好 了
has approved search on board and without
已经批准在船上搜索，没有
that it would not be optimal well Marcus
它不会是最佳马库斯
what does universal algorithm for
什么是 通用算法
solving all well-defined problems as
解决一切良好定义的问题
approved search on board so that's very
批准在船上搜索，这是非常的
much logic programming without that it
很多逻辑编程没有 它
would not be a Centanni optimum but then
不会是一个Centanni 最佳，但 随后
on the other hand because we have a very
另一方面因为我们有一个非常
pragmatic is also we focused on we
务实也是 我们专注于我们
cannula networks and and and some
插管网络和一些
optimal stuff such as gradient based
最佳的东西，如基于渐变
search and program space rather than
搜索和程序空间而不是
provably optimal things the logic
证明逻辑上最优的东西
programming does it certainly has a
编程确实有一个
usefulness in when you're trying to
在你努力的时候有用
construct something provably optimal or
构建 可证明最佳或最佳的 东西
probably good or something like that but
可能是好的或类似的但是
is it useful for for practical problems
它 是 针对实际 问题 有用
it's really useful at volunteer
它对志愿者来说真的很有用
improving the best theorem provers today
今天改进最好的定理证明
are not neural networks right no say our
不是神经网络对不对我们说
logic programming systems and they are
逻辑编程系统，他们是
much better theorem provers than most
比大多数人更好的定理证明
math students and the first or second
数学学生和第一或第二
semester on but for reasoning to for
学期上，但推理 为
playing games of go or chess or for
玩游戏或国际象棋或游戏
robots autonomous vehicles that operate
机器人，工作自主车
in the real world or object manipulation
在现实世界或对象操纵
you know you think learning yeah as long
你知道你 认为学习是的
as the problems have little to do with
因为问题与此无关
with C or improving themselves then as
用C或改进自己 然后作为
long as that is not the case you you
只要 你不是这样的话
just want to have better pattern
只想 拥有更好的模式
recognition so to build a self-driving
承认如此建立一个自我驾驶
car you want to have better pattern
汽车你想拥有更好的模式
recognition and
认可和
and pedestrian recognition and all these
和行人认可以及所有这些
things and you want to your minimum you
的东西，你想你的 最低限度你
want to minimize the number of false
想尽量减少 虚假的数量
positives which is currently is slowing
目前 正在放缓的积极因素
down self-driving cars in many ways and
在许多方面和自动驾驶汽车
and all that has very little to do with
和所有已经很少 做
logic programming yeah what are you most
逻辑编程是的，你最喜欢什么
excited about in terms of directions of
兴奋中 的 方向而言
artificial intelligence at this moment
人工智能在这一刻
in the next few years in your own
在你自己的未来几年
research and in the broader community so
研究和更广泛的社区
I think in the not so distant future we
我想在不远的将来 我们
will have for the first time
将是第 一次
little robots that learn like kids and I
像小孩和我一样学习的小机器人
will be able to say to the robot um look
能够对 机器人 说 呃看
here robot we are going to assemble a
在这里机器人，我们要组装一个
smartphone it's takes a slab of plastic
智能手机需要一块塑料
and the school driver and let's screw in
和学校的司机让我们搞砸了
the screw like that no no not like that
这样的螺丝不是不喜欢那样的
like so hmm not like that like that and
像这样嗯不喜欢 那样的
I don't have a data glove or something
我没有 数据手套什么的
he will see me and he will hear me and
他会看到我 ，他会听到我 和
he will try to do something with his own
他会尝试用自己的东西做点什么
actuators which will be really different
执行器将是真正不同的
from mine but he will understand the
从我的，但他会明白的
difference and will learn to imitate me
差异， 并会学会模仿我
but not in the supervised way where a
但不是以监督的方式在哪里
teacher is giving target signals for all
老师正在为所有人提供目标信号
his muscles all the time
他的肌肉一直都是
no by doing this high level imitation
不要做这种高水平的模仿
where he first has to learn to imitate
他首先必须学会 模仿
me and then to interpret these
我然后解释这些
additional noises coming from my mouth
来自我 口中的额外噪音
as helping helpful signals to to do that
作为帮助有用的信号来做到这一点
Hannah and then it will by itself come
汉娜 然后它会 自己 来
up with faster ways and more efficient
以更快的方式和更高效的方式
ways of doing the same thing and finally
最后 做同样 事情的方法
I stopped his learning algorithm and
我停止了他的学习算法
make a million copies and sell it and so
制作一百万份并出售它等等
at the moment this is not possible but
目前这是 不可能的， 但是
we already see how we are going to get
我们已经看到了我们将如何获得
there and you can imagine to the extent
那里， 你能想象 到的程度
that this works economically and cheaply
这在经济上和廉价上都有效
it's going to change everything almost
它几乎会改变一切
all our production is going to be
我们 所有 的生产都将 成为现实
affected by that and a much bigger wave
受这一点 ，一个更大的波
much bigger ai wave is coming than the
比a更大的ai波来了
one that we are currently witnessing
我们 目前目睹的一个
which is mostly about passive pattern
这主要是关于被动模式
recognition on your smartphone this is
在智能手机上识别这是
about active machines that shapes data
关于塑造数据的活动机器
Susy actions they are executing and they
他们正在执行的Susy行动和他们
learn to do that in a good way so many
学会以 这么多方式 做到这 一点
of the traditional industries are going
传统产业正在走向何方
to be affected by that all the companies
由 所有的公司的影响
that are building machines
那是 建筑机器
well equip these machines with cameras
为这些机器配备相机
and other sensors and they are going to
和其他传感器 ，他们将去
learn to solve all kinds of problems
学会解决各种 问题
through interaction with humans but also
通过与人类的互动而且
a lot on their own to improve what they
他们自己很多都在改进他们
already can do and lots of old economy
已经可以做很多旧经济了
is going to be affected by that and in
是要 通过 和 影响
recent years I have seen that all the
最近几年我 见过所有的
economy is actually waking up and
经济实际上是苏醒和
realizing that those vacations and are
意识到那些 假期 和 是
you optimistic about the future are you
你对未来感到乐观是 你
concerned there's a lot of people
关心的是很多人
concerned in the near term about the
在 短期内关注的是
transformation of the nature of work the
转变工作性质
kind of ideas that you just suggested
你刚才建议的那种想法
would have a significant impact of what
会 产生什么 重大 影响
kind of things could be automated are
有些 东西可以 自动化
you optimistic about that future are you
你对 未来是乐观的
nervous about that future and looking a
对这个未来感到紧张，并期待着
little bit farther into the future
进一步走向未来
there's people like you la musk - a
有像 你 这样的人 麝香 - a
rustle concerned about the existential
沙沙关注存在主义
threats of that future so in the near
那个未来的威胁就在附近
term job loss in the long term
从长远来看，长期失业
existential threat are these concerns to
生存的威胁是这些 担忧
you or yalta mele optimistic so let's
你或雅尔塔 mele乐观所以让我们
first address the near future we have
我们首先解决 不久的将来
had predictions of job losses for many
有许多人预测失业
decades for example when industrial
几十年，例如工业时
robots came along many people many
机器人很多人都来了
people predicted and lots of jobs are
人们预测并且有很多工作
going to get lost and in a sense say
会迷失方向 ，并在一定意义上说，
were right because back then there were
是对的，因为当时有
car factories and hundreds of people and
汽车工厂和数百人
these factories assembled cars and today
这些工厂组装汽车，今天
the same car factories have hundreds of
同样的汽车工厂有数百个
robots and maybe three guys watching the
机器人，也许还有三个人在看
robots on the other hand those countries
在另一方面机器人的国家
that have lots of robots per capita
有很多人均机器人
Japan Korea and Germany Switzerland a
日本韩国和德国瑞士 a
couple of other countries
其他几个国家
they have really low unemployment rates
他们有真正的低失业率
somehow all kinds of new jobs were
各种各样的新工作都是
created back then nobody anticipated
创造回来然后没人预料到
those jobs and decades ago I already
那些工作和几十年前 我 已经
said it's really easy to say which jobs
说很容易说出哪些工作
are going to get lost but it's really
会迷路但是真的
hard to predict the new ones 30 years
很难预测新的 30 年
ago who would have predicted all these
谁会预测 所有这些
people making money as YouTube bloggers
人们赚钱作为YouTube博主
200 years ago 60% of all people used to
200年前， 60％ 的人习惯了
work in agriculture today maybe 1% but
今天农业工作可能 只有1％但是
still only I don't know 5% unemployment
仍然只有我不知道 5％的失业率
lots of new jobs were created and Homo
创造了许多新的工作和 Homo
Luden's the the playing man is inventing
鲁登是那个正在发明的人
new jobs all the time most of these jobs
这些工作大多数都是新工作
are not existentially necessary for the
不是存在的必要条件
survival of our species there are only
我们物种的生存只有
very few existentially necessary jobs
很少有存在的必要工作
such as farming and building houses and
如农业 和建房和
and warming up the houses but less than
和升温的房子，但小于
10% of the population is doing that and
10％ 的人口正在这样做
most of these newly invented jobs are
大多数这些新发明的工作都是
about interacting with other people in
关于与其他人互动 的问题
new ways through new media and so on
通过新媒体的新方式等
getting new high types of kudos and
获得新的高级荣誉和荣誉
forms of likes and whatever and even
形式喜欢什么甚至是什么
making money through that so homo
通过 这样的同性恋 赚钱
Luden's the playing man doesn't want to
卢登的播放男人不 希望
be unemployed and that's why he is
失业，这就是为什么他 是
inventing new jobs all the time and he
他 一直在 创造新的 工作岗位
keeps considering these jobs as really
保持考虑到这些工作为真
important and is investing a lot of
重要而投入大量的
energy and hours of work into into those
能量和工作时间
and new jobs
和新的工作
it's quite beautifully put were really
这真是太棒了
nervous about the future because we
因为我们而 对 未来感到紧张
can't predict what kind of new jobs
无法预测什么样的新工作
would be created but your ultimate ly
会被创造， 但 你的终极
optimistic that we humans are so
乐观地认为我们人类是如此
Restless that we create
我们创造的 不安
and give meaning to newer in your jobs
并为你的工作赋予新意义
telling you likes on faith things that
告诉你喜欢 信仰的东西
get likes on Facebook or whatever the
在Facebook或 其他任何地方获得喜欢
social platform is so what about
社交平台是如此怎么样
long-term existential threat of AI where
人工智能 的长期 存在威胁在哪里
our whole civilization may be swallowed
我们整个文明都可能被吞噬
up by this ultra super intelligent
通过这超超级智能
systems maybe it's not going to be
系统可能不会
smaller DUP but I'd be surprised if B
较小的DUP，但如果B，我会感到惊讶
were B humans were the last step and the
B人类是最后一步而且是
evolution of the universe you you've
你所拥有的宇宙的进化
actually at this beautiful comment
实际上在这个美丽的评论
somewhere that I've seen saying that
在某个地方，我见过这么说
artificial quite insightful artificial
人工相当有洞察力的人工
general intelligence systems just like
一般情报系统就像
us humans will likely not want to
我们人类可能不会想要
interact with humans
与人类互动
they'll just interact amongst themselves
他们只会互相交流
just like ants interact amongst
就像蚂蚁之间的互动一样
themselves and only tangentially
他们自己， 只有切线
interact with humans hmm and it's quite
与人类互动嗯，它是相当的
an interesting idea that once we create
一旦我们创造了一个有趣的想法
a GI that will lose interest in humans
一种对人类失去兴趣的地理标志
and and have compete for their own
并且争夺自己
Facebook Likes on their own social
Facebook喜欢他们自己的社交
platforms so within that quite elegant
这样的平台非常优雅
idea how do we know in a hypothetical
我们如何在一个假设中知道
sense that there's not already
感觉到有没有
intelligent systems out there how do you
那里有智能系统你怎么样
think broadly of general intelligence
广泛地思考一般情报
greater than us how do we know it's out
比我们更大我们怎么知道它出来了
there mmm how would we know it's around
那 我们怎么会知道 它在附近
us and could it already be I'd be
我们可能已经是我了
surprised even with within the next few
在 接下来的 几个 内部甚至感到惊讶
decades or something like that we we
几十年或类似的 我们，我们什么
won't have a eyes that truly smarts in
不会有 真正 聪明 的 眼睛
every single way and better problem
每一种方式都有更好的问题
solvers and almost every single
解决者和几乎每一个人
important way and I'd be surprised as
重要的方式，我会感到惊讶
they wouldn't realize what we have
他们不会意识到我们拥有的东西
realized a long time ago which is that
很久 以前就意识到了 这 一点
almost all physical resources are not
几乎所有的物质资源都没有
here and this biosphere but for thou
在这里和这个生物圈，但对 你而言
the rest of the solar system gets 2
太阳系的其余部分得到2
billion times more solar energy than our
比 我们的 太阳能多十亿倍
little planet there's lots of material
小星球上有很多材料
out there that you can use to build
那里你可以用来建立
robots and self-replicating robot
机器人和自我复制机器人
factories and all this stuff and they
工厂和所有这些东西 和他们
are going to do that and there will be
将会这样做，并将有
scientists and curious and they will
科学家和 好奇的 他们会
explore what they can do and in the
探索他们可以做什么以及在做什么
beginning they will be fascinated by
一开始他们会着迷
life and by their own origins and our
生活和他们 自己的起源和我们的
civilization they will want to
他们想要的 文明
understand that completely just like
完全理解就是这样
people today would like to understand
今天人们想了解
how life works and um and also the
生活如何运作，嗯还有
history of our own existence and
我们自己的存在和历史
civilization and also on the physical
文明和物质
laws that created all of that so they in
制定 所有这些的 法律， 以便 他们进入
the beginning they will be fascinated my
一开始他们会为我着迷
life once they understand that I was
生活一旦他们明白我是
interest like anybody who loses interest
像任何失去兴趣的人一样感兴趣
and things he understands and then as
和他理解的东西，然后是
you said the most interesting sources
你说最有趣的 消息来源
information for them will be others of
他们的信息将是其他人的
their own kind
他们自己的那种
so at least in the long run there seems
所以至少从长远来看似乎
to be some sort of protection through
通过 这种方式 得到 某种保护
lack of interest on the other side
对方缺乏兴趣
and now it seems also clear as far as we
现在它也似乎很清楚， 只要我们
understand physics you need matter and
了解你需要的物理和物质
energy to compute and to build more
能量来计算和建立更多
robots and infrastructure and more AI
机器人和基础设施以及更多AI
civilization and III ecology is
文明和第三生态 是
consisting of trillions of different
由数万亿不同的组成
types of AIS and and so it seems
似乎是AIS的类型
inconceivable to me that this thing is
这件事是不可思议的
not going to expand some AI ecology not
不打算扩大一些人工智能生态学
controlled by one AI but one by
由一个AI控制，但由一个控制
trillions of different types of AI is
数以万亿计的不同类型的人工智能
competing and all kinds of quickly
竞争和各种快速
evolving and disappearing ecological
生态的演变和消失
niches in ways that we cannot fathom at
我们无法理解的方式
the moment but it's going to expand
那一刻，但它会扩大
limited by Lightspeed and physics it's
受到Lightspeed和物理学 的限制
going to expand and and now we realize
要扩大，现在我们意识到
that the universe is still young it's
宇宙还很年轻 很
only 13.8 billion years old
只有138亿年
and it's going to be a thousand times
它将 成千上万次
older than that so there's plenty of
比 这 更大 ，所以有很多
time to conquer the entire universe and
时间征服 整个宇宙 和
to fill it with intelligence and senders
用智力和发送者来填补它
and receivers such that AI scan trouble
和接收器，以便AI扫描麻烦
the way they are traveling in our labs
他们在我们 实验室 旅行的方式
today which is by radio from sender to
今天通过无线电从发送者到
receiver and let's call the current age
接收器让我们称之为当前年龄
of the universe one Eon
宇宙中的一个Eon
one Eon now it will take just a few eons
一个Eon现在只需要几个月
from now and the entire visible universe
从现在起和整个可见的宇宙
is going to be full of that stuff and
将充满那些东西和
let's look ahead to a time when the
让我们展望未来
universe is going to be one thousand
宇宙 将成千上万
times older than it is now they will
比 现在 年龄大的 时候他们会
look back and they will say look almost
回头看，他们会说几乎看起来
immediately after the Big Bang
大爆炸后立刻
only a few eons later the entire
整整只有几个月
universe started to become intelligent
宇宙开始变得聪明
now to your question how do we see
现在问 你怎么 看？
whether anything like that has already
是否有类似的东西已经存在
happened or is already in a more
发生了或者已经发生了
advanced stage in some other part of the
在其他一些部分的高级阶段
universe of the visible universe we are
我们是 宇宙 的可见宇宙
trying to look out there and nothing
试图看那里 什么都没有
like that has happened so far or is that
这样的 事情到目前为止 还是那样
her
她的
do you think we'll recognize it or
你认为我们会认出 它吗？
how do we know it's not among us how do
我们怎么知道它不在我们中间怎么做
we know planets aren't in themselves
我们知道行星本身并不存在
intelligent beings how do we know ants
智能生物我们怎么知道蚂蚁
seen as a collective are not much
被视为集体并不多
greater intelligence in our own these
我们自己的智慧更高
kinds of ideas no but it was a boy I was
各种 想法没有，但它是一个男孩，我是
thinking about these things and I
思考这些事情 和我
thought hmm maybe it has already
以为嗯也许它已经存在了
happened because back then I know I knew
发生的事， 因为 那时我知道 我知道
I learned from popular physics books
我从流行的物理书籍中学到了
that the structure the large-scale
那个结构大规模
structure of the universe is not
宇宙的结构不是
homogeneous and you have these clusters
同质的 ，你有这些集群
of galaxies and then in between there
星系然后在那之间
are these huge empty spaces and I
这些巨大的 空地和我
thought hmm maybe they aren't really
以为嗯也许他们不是真的
empty it's just that in the middle of
把它倒空只是在中间
that some AI civilization already has
一些人工智能文明已经存在
expanded and then has covered a bottle
扩大，然后盖了一瓶
of a billion light-years diameter and is
直径十亿光年 ，是
using all the energy of all the stars
使用所有的星星的 所有 能量
within that bubble for its own
在那个泡沫中为 自己
unfathomable purposes and so it always
不可思议的目的，所以它总是如此
happened and we just failed to interpret
发生了，我们只是没有解释
the signs but then alarmed effect
标志但后来惊慌失措
gravity by itself explains the
引力本身解释了
large-scale structure of the universe
宇宙的大规模结构
and that this is not a convincing
并认为 这是不令人信服的
explanation and then I thought maybe
解释然后我想也许吧
maybe it's the dark matter because as
也许这是暗物质，因为
far as we know today 80% of the
据我们今天所知， 80％的人
measurable matter is invisible and we
可测量的物质是看不见的 ， 我们
know that because otherwise our galaxy
知道， 因为否则我们的银河系
or other galaxies would fall apart they
或者 其他星系会分崩离析
would they are rotating too quickly and
它们会旋转得太快吗？
then the idea was maybe all us he is AI
那个想法可能就是我们所有人都是AI
civilizations and hourly out there they
文明和他们每小时出去
they just invisible because they are
他们只是 看不见， 因为 他们是
really efficient in using the energies
真正有效地使用能量
at their own local systems and that's
在他们自己的本地系统，那是
why they appear dark to us but this is
为什么他们对我们来说显得很黑暗， 但这是
awesome at a convincing explanation
令人信服的解释令人敬畏
because then the question becomes why is
因为那时问题就变成了原因
there
那里
are there still any visible stars left
还剩下任何明显的星星吗？
in our own galaxy which also must have a
在我们自己的星系中， 也必须有一个
lot of dark matter so that is also not a
很多暗物质也是 如此
convincing thing and today I like to
令人信服的事情，今天我喜欢
think it's quite plausible that maybe
认为这可能是相当合理的
are the first at least in our local
是至少在我们当地 的第一个
light cone within a few hundreds of
几十个 内 的 光锥
millions of light years that we can
我们可以拥有数百万光年
reliably observe is there exciting to
可靠的观察是令人兴奋的
you it will might be the first and it
您它将可能 是第一个和它
would make us much more important
会让我们变得 更加重要
because if we mess it up through a
因为如果我们 搞砸了
nuclear war then then maybe this will
那么核战争那么可能就是这样
have an effect on the on the on the
对对对 的 影响
development on of the entire universe so
整个宇宙的发展如此
let's not mess it up let's not mess it
让我们不要搞砸 了， 不要搞砸它
up Union thank you so much for talking
了 联盟谢谢你这么多说话
today I really appreciate it it's my
今天我真的很 感激它是我的
pleasure
乐趣
you
您